[
  {
    "question": "What are the main elements in the definition of software architecture?",
    "answers": [0, 1, 2, 3],
    "options": [
      "Set of structures",
      "Software elements",
      "Relations",
      "Properties"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Structures that can answer which CPUs software elements are executed on are named...",
    "answers": [0],
    "options": ["Allocation", "Component-and-Connector", "Module", "None"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What TYPE of architectural pattern can this be classified as? <img src=\"images/a8buj2.webp\"/>",
    "answers": [1],
    "options": ["Allocation", "Component-and-connector", "Fictive", "Modular"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What pattern can be used to ensure a single instance of a class?",
    "answers": [3],
    "options": ["Abstract Factory", "Composite", "Observer", "Singleton"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What TYPE of architectural pattern can this be classified as? <img src=\"images/gnn16q.webp\"/>",
    "answers": [0],
    "options": ["Allocation", "Component-and-connector", "Fictive", "Modular"]
  },
  {
    "question": "The most important technical factor that contributes to the architecture is...",
    "answers": [3],
    "options": [
      "Architect's experise",
      "Development tools",
      "Stakeholder's goals",
      "Quality attributes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the main influences of the stakeholders related to software architectures?",
    "answers": [0, 2, 3],
    "options": ["Business", "Programming Language", "Project", "Technical"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Structures that can answer what parts of the system can run in parallel are...",
    "answers": [1],
    "options": ["Allocation", "Component-and-Connector", "Module", "None"]
  },
  {
    "question": "A quality attribute scenario is used to describe...",
    "answers": [1],
    "options": [
      "Quality assurance",
      "Quality requirements",
      "Quality system design",
      "The allocation view"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What parameters are typically used in performance models?",
    "answers": [0, 1, 3],
    "options": [
      "Arrival rate",
      "Network bandwidth",
      "Recovery time",
      "Schedule algorithm"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What view is most relevant for the end user? (4+1 view model)",
    "answers": [1],
    "options": ["Development", "Logical", "Process", "Physical"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is important for getting a good object-oriented design?",
    "answers": [0, 1, 3],
    "options": [
      "Abstraction/generalization",
      "Delegation",
      "High coupling",
      "High cohesion"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What do you call a collection of patterns that build on each other to generate a system?",
    "answers": [2],
    "options": [
      "Architectural Pattern",
      "Idioms",
      "Pattern Language",
      "Pattern styles"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What Type of architectural pattern has been used here? <img src=\"images/c0tacc.webp\"/>",
    "answers": [3],
    "options": ["Allocation", "Component-and-connector", "Fictive", "Modular"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Important keywords related to the description of a design pattern are...",
    "answers": [0, 1, 3],
    "options": ["Context", "Problem", "Programming language", "Solution"]
  },
  {
    "question": "A safe architectural design decision is named:",
    "answers": [0],
    "options": ["Non-risk", "Risk", "Sensitivity point", "Tradeoff point"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What analysis models exist for Usability?",
    "answers": [2],
    "options": [
      "Conceptual frameworks",
      "Markov models",
      "None",
      "Real-time scheduling"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which structures from the textbook can be classified as allocation structures?",
    "answers": [1, 3],
    "options": ["Data model", "Implementation", "Uses", "Work assignment"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What view has the main focus on non-functional requirements such as availability & scalability?",
    "answers": [2, 3],
    "options": ["Development", "Logical", "Process", "Physical"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What analysis models exist for Performance?",
    "answers": [2, 3],
    "options": [
      "Conceptual frameworks",
      "Component interaction metrics",
      "Queuing",
      "Real-time scheduling"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What types of views are described in the textbook?",
    "answers": [0, 1, 3],
    "options": ["Allocation", "Component-and-connector", "Dynamic", "Module"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Description of patterns specific to a programming language is called...",
    "answers": [2],
    "options": ["Architectural pattern", "Design pattern", "Idioms", "Tactics"]
  },
  {
    "question": "How can an architecture affect business goals of a system?",
    "answers": [0, 2],
    "options": [
      "Add value",
      "Support cloud computing",
      "Faster to market",
      "Less system crash"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Description of fundamental structural organization or schema for software systems is called...",
    "answers": [0],
    "options": ["Architectural pattern", "Design pattern", "Idioms", "Tactics"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What pattern can be used to ensure that single and multiple objects can be treated similarly?",
    "answers": [1],
    "options": ["Abstract Factory", "Composite", "Singleton", "Template Method"]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what view can ER-modeling typically be used? (4+1 view model)",
    "answers": [1],
    "options": ["Development", "Logical", "Physical", "Scenario"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What questions do ATAM produce answers to?",
    "answers": [0, 2],
    "options": [
      "Is the architecture suitable?",
      "Which architecture is best?",
      "Which of the architectures is most suitable",
      "Which gives best cost/benefit?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Structures that allow reasoning about how primary functionality is assigned to units are named:",
    "answers": [2],
    "options": ["Allocation", "Component-and-Connector", "Module", "None"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is this? <img src=\"images/l57v9n.webp\"/>",
    "answers": [3],
    "options": [
      "Risk themes",
      "Sensitivity points",
      "Tradeoff points",
      "Utility tree"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What pattern can be used to implement/maintain several almost identical pieces of code?",
    "answers": [3],
    "options": ["Abstract Factory", "Composite", "Observer", "Template Method"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What pattern can be used to ensure that a change of one object influences other objects?",
    "answers": [2],
    "options": ["Abstract Factory", "Composite", "Observer", "Template Method"]
  },
  {
    "question": "A decision that will affect two or more fighting quality attributes is named:",
    "answers": [3],
    "options": ["Non-risk", "Risk", "Sensitivity point", "Tradeoff point"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Tactics are in a software architecture context...",
    "answers": [3],
    "options": [
      "Architectural design process",
      "Architectural patterns",
      "Design patterns",
      "Primitive design techniques"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How can you implement variation points for software product line in code?",
    "answers": [1, 2],
    "options": [
      "Client-server pattern",
      "Generalization",
      "Overloading",
      "Singleton Pattern"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Modeling of architecture for availability is typically carried out for determining...",
    "answers": [0, 2],
    "options": [
      "Failure rates",
      "Latency",
      "Recovery times",
      "Parallel processes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How is the scoping of the variation points in the software product line for this scenario? \"Have you developed something on our software product line?\" \"Yeah I tried. The software product line did not help much. Had to implement most of it from scratch!\"",
    "answers": [2],
    "options": ["Just right", "Too narrow", "Too broad", "No scope"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What adoption strategy for software product lines is used in this company? Bill Gates: \"When I started my company, I decided that we should go for a software product line from day one!\"",
    "answers": [1, 3],
    "options": ["Bottom-up", "Proactive", "Reactive", "Top-down"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What analysis models exist for Availability?",
    "answers": [2, 3],
    "options": [
      "Coupling metrics",
      "Cost models",
      "Markov models",
      "Statistical models"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The term for a representation of a coherent set of architectural elements is...",
    "answers": [3],
    "options": ["Architecture", "Module", "Structure", "View"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What view represents an abstraction of the most important requirements? (4+1 view model)",
    "answers": [3],
    "options": ["Development", "Logical", "Process ยง Scenario"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the TA in ATAM an abbreviation for?",
    "answers": [3],
    "options": [
      "Testability Attributes",
      "Testability Analysis",
      "Traceability Analysis",
      "Tradeoff Analysis"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are typical outputs of the ATAM?",
    "answers": [0, 2, 3],
    "options": [
      "Concise architecture",
      "Cost/benefit analysis",
      "Map tactics to quality requirements",
      "Utility tree"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A decision that will affect only one quality attribute is named:",
    "answers": [2],
    "options": ["Non-risk", "Risk", "Sensitivity point", "Tradeoff point"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are typical outputs of the ATAM?",
    "answers": [0, 1, 2],
    "options": [
      "Set of nonrisks",
      "Set of risks",
      "Set of risk themes",
      "Set of technologies"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is this? <img src=\"images/xwu69d.webp\"/>",
    "answers": [0],
    "options": [
      "Analysis of architectural approaches",
      "Quality replication",
      "Risk theme list",
      "Sensitivity review"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are typical outputs of the ATAM?",
    "answers": [2, 3],
    "options": [
      "Initial system implementation",
      "Project plan",
      "Sensitivity points",
      "Tradeoff points"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is gained from doing a CBAM compared to doing an ATAM?",
    "answers": [0],
    "options": [
      "Economical analysis",
      "Simpler architecture",
      "Tradeoff analysis",
      "Quality analysis"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which architectural strategy should be chosen from the numbers? <img src=\"images/13c6tp.webp\"/>",
    "answers": [1],
    "options": ["1", "2", "3", "4"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What adoption strategy for software product lines is used in this company? \"In our company, the programmers were tired creating all these products from scratch. So we decided to do a software product line!\"",
    "answers": [0, 2],
    "options": ["Bottom-up", "Proactive", "Reactive", "Top-down"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Categorize the following characteristic: \"Support multi-tenancy\"",
    "answers": [0],
    "options": ["Cloud", "Not cloud"]
  },
  {
    "question": "How is the scoping of the following scenario? \"Have you now developed something on our <b>new</b> software product line? Isn't it good?\" \"Well... This time I tried to implement three new products, but only one fitted into the software product line. Bummer!\"",
    "answers": [0],
    "options": ["Too narrow", "Just right", "Too broad", "No scope"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Categorize the following characteristic: \"HDFS file system\"",
    "answers": [0],
    "options": ["Cloud", "Not cloud"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main characteristic from an Edge dominant system?",
    "answers": [1],
    "options": [
      "Many users",
      "Depend on input from users",
      "Agile development",
      "Guitar-based"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Categorize the following characteristic: \"Heterogeneous clients\"",
    "answers": [1],
    "options": ["Not cloud", "Cloud"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the term that describes people who both produce and consume content?",
    "answers": [0],
    "options": ["Prosumers", "Conproders", "Cores", "Edgers"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Categorize the following characteristic: \"Private hardware\"",
    "answers": [1],
    "options": ["Cloud", "Not cloud"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is important when designing the architecture for the CORE of an Edge dominant system?",
    "answers": [0, 2],
    "options": [
      "Highly modular",
      "Provide many services",
      "Highly robust",
      "Large team"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Categorize the following characteristic: \"FAT file system\"",
    "answers": [0],
    "options": ["Not cloud", "Cloud"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Requirements in Edge dominant systems are usually established from...",
    "answers": [2],
    "options": [
      "Interviews",
      "Talking to customers",
      "Web forums",
      "Company management"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the total benefit obtained from architectural strategy 2? <img src=\"images/dygp3m.webp\"/>",
    "answers": [1],
    "options": ["600", "1050", "2225", "5000"]
  }
]
